Rick Clark

Salt Lake City, UT 84103 rickdclark48@gmail.com 2067958619

I am a laboratory technologist with two years of experience in innate immunology. Recently, I earned the Full Stack Developer Certificate from the University of Utah Coding Bootcamp. Please visit my Github repository and portfolio site to see my projects (links below).

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Laboratory Technologist I

ARUP Laboratories, Cellular and Innate Immunology Division - Salt Lake City, UT April 2016 to July 2018

The Cellular and Innate Immunology Division investigates the presence of innate immune deficiencies, the effectiveness of pharmacological treatment, and the specific pathology behind immune disorders in patients. As a technologist, I completed assays, interpreted results, and ensured the accuracy of reported data. I gained expertise in operating a Flow Cytometer, a Luminex instrument, and I became experienced with Cell Culture.

Student Doctor

Primary Care Clerkship - Orem, UT January 2013 to January 2015

Worked as a student doctor at the University of Utah Health Care Clinic in Orem, Utah and in Murray, Utah . My responsibilities were to record patient histories and participate in physical exams and special procedures. I worked under the direction of Dr. Miguel Villalobos and Dr. Keith Vancuran.

Research Assistant NIH Grant

University of Utah Department of Trauma Surgery - Salt Lake City, UT May 2013 to August 2013

I participated in a literature review exploring the relationship between blood thinners, traumaticbrain injuries, and mortality in elderly individuals with atrial fibrillation. I worked under thesupervision of the P.I. Dr. Ram Nirula.

Research Assistant Electrophysiology

Brigham Young University College of Life Sciences - Provo, UT January 2010 to June 2012

I carried out electrophysiology experiments on rat and mice hippocampal cells. My participation contributed to two publications.

HIV Counselor

STD Testing - Salt Lake City, UT September 2010 to January 2012 As a volunteer counselor, I performed client testing for HIV, educated clients on risk reduction, and participated in public outreach.

Intern Maternal and Reproductive Health Clinic

USAID Reproductive Clinic - Cochabamba, Bolivia June 2010 to August 2010

I offered phlebotomy services, aided in clinical visits and surgeries, and obtained vitals and history from patients.

Education

Full Stack Web Developer in Trilogy Coding Bootcamp

University of Utah Professional Education - Salt Lake City, UT August 2018 to February 2019

Withdrawal - No Degree Awarded

University of Utah School of Medicine - Salt Lake City, UT August 2012 to August 2015

B.S. in Physiology and Developmental Biology

Brigham Young University - Provo, UT August 2006 to April 2012

Skills

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, React (Less than 1 year), Medical Terminology (2 years), Pharmacology (2 years)

Links

http://rick.clark.s3-website-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/

https://github.com/RClark4958?tab=repositories

Certifications/Licenses

Professional Education - Coding Bootcamp Full Stack Developer Certificate Issued by the University of Utah